sacredheart.edu 2019-07-01

# Privacy Statement | Sacred Heart University Connecticut

_Last modified: May 22, 2018_

Sacred Heart University's policy is to respect the privacy of all website visitors to the extent permitted by law. This online privacy statement is intended to help you understand:

  * What types of information we collect
  * How we use information we collect
  * How we share information we collect
  * How we store and secure information we collect
  * How to access and control your information
  * How we transfer information we collect internationally
  * Other important privacy information
  * How to contact us
  * GDPR: Additional privacy considerations

## Types of Information We Collect

There are four types of information that this site may collect during your visit:

  * network traffic logs
  * web visit logs
  * cookies
  * voluntary information

## **How We Use Information We Collect  
**

### **Network Traffic Logs**

In the course of ensuring network security and consistent service for all users, the University employs software programs to do such things as monitor network traffic, identify unauthorized access or access to nonpublic information, detect computer viruses and other software that might damage University computers or the network, and monitor and tune the performance of the University network.

In the course of such monitoring, these programs may detect such information as email headers, addresses from network packets, and other information. Information from these activities is used only for the purpose of maintaining the security and performance of the University's networks and computer systems. Personally identifiable information from these activities is not released to external parties without your consent unless required by law.

### **Web Visit Logs**

University web sites routinely collect and store information from online visitors to help manage those sites and improve service. This information includes the pages visited on the site, the date and time of the visit, the internet address (URL or IP address) of the referring site, the domain name and IP address from which the access occurred, the version of browser used, the capabilities of the browser, and search terms used on our search engines.

This site makes no attempt to identify individual visitors from this information. Any personally identifiable information is not released to external parties without your consent unless required by law.

### **Cookies**

Cookies are pieces of information stored by your web browser on behalf of a Web site and returned to the Web site on request. This site may use cookies for two purposes: to carry data about your current session at the site from one web page to the next, and to identify you to the site between visits. If you prefer not to receive cookies, you may turn them off in your browser preferences, or may set your browser preferences to ask you before accepting a new cookie. Some pages may not function properly if cookies are turned off. Unless otherwise notified on this site, we will not store data, other than for these two purposes, in cookies.

Cookies remain on your computer, and accordingly we neither store cookies on our computers nor forward them to any external parties. Unless otherwise notified on this site, we do not use cookies to track your movement among different Web sites and do not exchange cookies with other entities.

### **Voluntary Information**

In the course of using this web site, you may choose to provide us with information to help us serve your needs. For example, you may send us electronic mail (through a mailer or a web form) to request information, you may sign up for a mailing list, or you may send us your address so we may send you an application or other materials. Any personally-identifiable information you send us will be used only for the purpose indicated.

In addition to facilitating basic communication with you, the information we hold helps us enhance your experiences on our web site and the efficacy of our communications with you. For example, by holding your basic personal information, we can automatically fill out transactional forms with that data to save you time and effort.

We use personal information to communicate essential information about transactions, such as an electronic receipt for a tuition payment or a confirmation for an event registration.

We also use it to inform you about Sacred Heart University events, programs, and services of potential interest, unless you have opted out of such communications.

## How We Share Information We Collect

We will not sell, exchange, or otherwise distribute your personally-identifiable information without your consent, except to the extent required by law. We do not retain the information longer than necessary for normal operations.

Each web page requesting information discloses the purpose of that information. If you do not wish to have the information used in that manner, you are not required to provide it. Please refer to the contact information listed below with any questions or concerns on the use of personally-identifiable information.

##   
How We Store and Secure Information We Collect

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

The personal information we collect is stored in databases and files that are protected by passwords and firewalls. In addition, online forms used for financial transactions are secured with SSL encryption technology to ensure the safety of sensitive information transmitted through them (e.g., credit card information). When credit card information is stored, it is done so only in an encrypted format.

While we implement safeguards designed to protect your information, no security system is 100% safe. Due to the inherent nature of the internet, we cannot guarantee that data, during transmission through the internet or while stored on our systems or otherwise in our care, is absolutely safe from intrusion by others. We will respond to requests about this within a reasonable timeframe.

## How to Access and Control your Information

You have the right to request a copy of your information, to object to our use of your information (including for marketing purposes), to request the correction, deletion or restriction of your information, or to request your information in a structured, electronic format.

## How We Transfer Information We Collect Internationally

We collect information globally and primarily store that information in the United States. We transfer, process and store your information outside of your country of residence, to wherever we, Sacred Heart University, or our third-party service providers operate. Whenever we transfer your information, we take steps to protect it.

## Changes to Our Privacy Policy and other Important Information

Sacred Heart University may change this Privacy Policy from time to time and without prior notice. We suggest that you regularly review our Privacy Policy for changes or updates. Your continued use of the Sacred Heart website after any changes are made will be considered your acceptance of the changes.   
The University web sites provide links to other web sites or resources (You can tell you are leaving a Sacred Heart University web site by noting the URL of the destination site). We do not control these sites and resources, we do not endorse them, and we are not responsible for their availability, content, or delivery of services. In particular, external sites are not bound by the University's online privacy policy; they may have their own policies or none at all.

## How to Contact Us

Any questions or concerns you may have concerning this Privacy Policy, or the practices described herein, can be directed to Sacred Heart University, Privacy, 5151 Park Avenue, Fairfield, CT 06825 or [privacy@sacredheart.edu](mailto:privacy@sacredheart.edu). 

## GDPR: Additional Privacy Considerations

### **Usage of Personal Information**

As of May 25, 2018, the General Data Protection Regulation (EU) 2016/679 ("GDPR") is in effect. The GDPR requires that a valid legal basis is used in processing personal data. In certain countries, there are specific legal bases that we rely on in order to use personal information. They include but are not limited to the following:

### **Contract Performance**

The use of your personal information may be necessary to perform the agreement you have with us. For example, this is necessary to establish your agreement with the University, as well as to create and maintain your account and secure accessibility as a student.

### **Legitimate Analysis, Improvements, and Administration**

We may use your personal information for our legitimate interests. For example, we rely on our legitimate interest to analyze and improve the content on our websites, to send you notifications about information about Sacred Heart University or to use your personal information for administrative, fraud detection or legal purposes.

### **Legal Obligation**

We may use your personal information to comply with legal requirements, per law enforcement and government. Personal information (PII) may be disclosed to law enforcement officials and government agencies, and private parties as we believe necessary. Sacred Heart University must comply with applicable law(s) and legal process to protect our rights, including any parties involved, in order to prevent or cease unethical or illegal activity. If the government asks for information, we must comply.

### **Consent**

At times, we may request your consent to conduct certain actions with your personal information. When requesting your consent, we are transparent in ensuring you know what you are consenting to.

### **Best Practice Security Measures**

Sacred Heart University takes seriously the protection of personal information from unauthorized access and disclosure. Given the best circumstances, however, no one can guarantee the absolute certainty of complete security regarding transmission of information over the Internet or storage of data.

### **Data Retention**

Your personal information will be retained as needed in order to fulfill the purposes for which it was collected. This includes the retention and use of personal information to comply with our business and legal obligations, enforce our agreements, and resolve disputes if and when they arise.

### **Links to Other Sites**

The Sacred Heart Privacy Policy does not apply to third-party websites or services. As the University website may contain links to other websites and services, we are not responsible for the security practices and policies, privacy, or the content of those websites and/or services. Any information that you provide on or to a third-party website or service is directly provided to the owner of that website or service and is subject to that party's privacy policy.
